--==藏身之所==--
片名：《藏身之所》
我要跟Parker谈谈今天的推广活动 I'm going to talk to Parker about my promotion today.
我今天要跟帕克談談我升職的事
最坏的情况下，你要提前两周 In the worst-case scenario you're two weeks ahead of me,
在日常生存自救方面你比我有經驗
你在Marais区域不是有套小别墅 you get a gorgeous little apartment in the Marais.
你在瑪萊區有一處漂亮小房子 （法國巴黎一區名）
如果我不想住在哪里呢？ What if I don't want to live in the Marais?
要是我不想住在瑪萊區呢？
我们可以住到别出去，然后 We couId live somewhere else, then.
那我們可以住到別的地方
是吗？好的 Yeah? Yeah.
- 是嗎？ - 是的
我们可以去底特律 We could go to Detroit.
我們可以去底特律
底特律？ Detroit?
底特律？
是啊，你可以见到我爸爸妈妈 Yeah, you could meet my mom and dad.
是的，你可以見見我父母
你还能看到我姐姐，她有一家小面包店 You can meet my sister.She owns a bakery,
你可以見到我妹妹，她有一家麵包店
会让你变胖~ and she will make you fat.
她會把你養肥的
在我回医院之前，还有六个小时 I have six hours before I have to go back to the hospital.
在我得回醫院前我還有6個小時
你想跟我回到床上去？ You want to go back into bed with me?
你想跟我一起回床上去嗎？
嗯 I do.
我想
但是我一上午都有会要开 But I got back-to-back meetings all morning.
但我一上午都要連續開會
太惨了 Too bad for you.
你真不幸
是啊，我知道 Yeah, I know.
是啊，我知道
但是，我得进去了 But I got to get in.
但是我得走了
可能已经有25人在门外 There's probabIy already 25 people
可能已經有25個人
排队和等待了 lined up outside the door, waiting.
排隊等在門外了
我喜欢你讲法语的样子 I love when you speak French.
我喜歡你說法語
通信检查 Satcom check.
衛星通訊身份核對
呼叫 9 3 维克多 呼叫 2 Echo Nine Three Victor Echo Two.
E-9-3-V-E-2
中心 Ops Center.
行動中心
这里是安全屋，我们开业啦 This is safe house 7-R.we're open for business.
這是7-R號安全屋，已開啟使用
确认 Confirmed.
確認
留活口么？ Any reservations?
有「預約客人」嗎？ （酒店用語作通訊代號）
不在考虑中 Nothing in the registry.
未查到任何記錄
步行进入？ Walk-ins?
有「臨時散客」嗎？
不需要，三小时内重新确认 Not expected.Reconfirm in three hours.
沒有，三小時後重新確認
明白 Understood.
明白
matt 你的手机，真的吗？ Matt? Your cell, really?
馬特？你打來的，真的嗎？
放心，我已经加密了 Relax, l've got an encryption packet.
放心，電話加密了
你知道的，我永远不会放心 You know me,I never relax.
你瞭解我的，我從不放心
Watch the cholesterol,old man.
小心膽固醇偏高，老頭
You sound like Miriam.
你聽起來像米裏亞姆
So, what's new in Cape Town?
開普敦有什麼新消息嗎？
Nothing, nothing.
什麼都沒，什麼都沒
I updated my Surveillance Target Analysis.It's compIete now.
我更新了監視目標分析系統，現在已經完工了
Yeah, that's an exit report.It's not due until you leave.
好的，那是離職報告，你走的時候才弄的
Exactly. Exactly.And when is that?
確實，確實，那什麼時候走呢？
How long has it been?
已經多久了？
Twelve months.
12個月了
Well, talk to me in another four.
好吧，四個月後再跟我說吧
David, I'm dying here.
大衛，我要悶死在這兒了
What's happening with the post in Paris?
巴黎的崗位怎麼樣了？
One slot,37 applicants.
一個名額，37份申請
Every one of them with more field experience than you.
所有人都比你更有實際經驗
How am I supposed to get more experience?
我要怎麼才能弄到更多經驗？
I'm staring at four walls all day.
我整天盯著四面牆
I got passed up on Rome,then Berlin.
我錯過了羅馬，接著是柏林
You said yourseIf,my evaluation was excellent.
你自己說的，我的評價是優秀
Just put it in front of Whitford.
跟威特福德當面說就是了
I know he'll see that l'm ready to go,I'm all in.
我知道他會看出我可以離開了，我累死了
Matt, I know this has been hard,
馬特，我知道很不容易
but it's the way the system works.
但是系統就是這樣運作的
Look, I'll talk to Whitford about Paris,but I can't promise anything.
聽著，我會跟威特福德談談巴黎崗位的，但我不能做任何承諾
Look, I've got to go.
聽著，我得掛了
Don't worry,I'm looking after you, okay?
別擔心，我會罩著你的，好嗎？
Yeah, I know,I know, I know.
是啊，我懂，我懂，我懂
This is not a negotiation.
這不是談判
It's 10 million.
事關一千萬美元
You'll get the file,and if the money
你會拿到資料的，如果錢...
is not in the account by 3:00 p.m. ,
沒有在下午3點前匯到賬戶裏
I'll take it to another buyer.
我就把資料賣給另一個買家
How do we know that you won't do that anyway?
我們怎麼知道你最終不會那樣做？
You don't.
你確實不知道
Here you are, sir.
就在這兒，先生
Alec, how are you?
亞力克，你好嗎？
Petrus, 1972.
柏圖斯，1972年的
You look good.
你氣色不錯
I do, don't I?
是不錯，對吧？
So, how are things at MI6?
在軍情六局混得好嗎？
The usual.Same bureaucratic bullshit and appalling remuneration.
老樣子，一樣的官僚作風和微薄薪水
Life of a government man.
典型的公務員生活
Mmm-hmm.
嗯哼
So. . .
那麼...
The original file.
原始文件
Dates,transactions, names.
日期，交易記錄，名字
A bargain at triple the price.
要是講價就三倍價格
Take a look.
看看吧
Hmm.
嗯
I've been waiting a long time for this.
我已經為此等了很久了
Tobin. . .
托賓
What's in that box is going to make
那小東西裏的資料會讓你
the world a smaller place for you,
讓你我都覺得
for both of us.
世界好小
I got your account.
我有你的賬戶
You get your cut 24 hours after transaction.
交易完成後24小時你就會拿到錢
Some of our old bosses aren't going to be happy
你的一些老上司會對公開
these files are out in the open.
這些資料感到很不高興的
Do I make you nervous?
我讓你害怕了嗎？
Always.Good.
- 一貫如此 - 很好
You want her?
你想要她？
Please, listen to me.
請聽我說
I had nothing to do with this.
我與此無關
Stop.
站住
Let's go.
我們走
Tobin, you have to believe me.
托賓，你得相信我
I knew nothing about any of that.
我對此一無所知
Did you know if anybody was following you?
你知道是否有人跟蹤你嗎？
No, I don't think anybody was following me.
不，我不覺得有誰在跟蹤我
I swear on my life,Tobin, I had absolutely. . .
我用性命擔保，托賓，我絕對...
Slow down.
減速
We're going by foot.
我們步行
Head towards the square.
朝廣場走
Move! Move! Move!
行動！行動！行動！
We're heading west.
我們在朝西走
Holland Street.Move, move.
荷蘭街，行動，行動
Excuse me, sir.Thank you.
抱歉，先生，謝謝
My name is Tobin Frost.
我叫托賓·弗羅斯特
Linklater.
林克萊特
When?
什麼時候？
Lock down the consulate.
封鎖領事館
Get me a team in the Situation Room in five minutes.
五分鐘內派一組人來局勢研究室
I want everything we got on Tobin Frost.
我想要所有托賓·弗羅斯特的資料
Yes, ma'am.
好的，女士
Is it him?Yep.
- 是他嗎？ - 是的
Whitford know?
威特福德知道嗎？
I'm on my way there now.
我正要去通知呢
Sir,place your finger in there until I tell you to stop.
先生，在這兒按下手指直到我說停止
Thank you.
謝謝
So how long has he been playing in your backyard?
他在你後院搗亂多久了？
We're working to get you that answer right now.
我們正努力幫您尋找答案
Meaning you don't know.
這就是說你不知道
No, meaning,we're looking into it.
不，這是說我們正在調查情況
The guy goes rogue,he spends nine years
這傢伙無法無天，他9年來都在
selling out the Agency to all takers.
出賣情報機構給所有買家
To Russia, China, Iran,you name it.
俄羅斯，中國，伊朗，全都有
The guy is just not going to prance
這傢伙沒有好理由不會就這樣
into an American consulate without good reason.
大搖大擺走進美國領事館的
All right, listen up.
好的，聽著
Everybody off the phone.
所有人放下電話
Tobin Frost has just waltzed his way
托賓·弗羅斯特剛剛明目張膽走進了
into a U.S. Consulate in Cape Town, South Africa.
南非開普敦的美國領事館
Now this man,without question,
這傢伙，毫無疑問
is one of the most notorious traders that we've got.
是我們掌握的最臭名昭著的交易人之一
Errington, call up his background profile.
艾琳頓，調出他的背景資料
Tobin Frost was recruited into the Agency in 1984.
托賓·弗羅斯特1984被招入情報局
He tested off the charts in aptitude for psychological field work.
他在心理學方面非常有天賦
His first assignment was in Lebanon,in January 1985.
他的首次任務是在黎巴嫩，1985年一月
Three months later,he captured and flipped
三個月後，他俘獲並收買了
a high-ranking Hezbollah leader.
一個高級真主黨領導人
Over the next severaI years,
接下來幾年裏
Frost successfuIIy questioned and recruited many high-vaIue individuaIs.
弗羅斯特成功審查並收買了許多很有價值的人員
He became known as an expert manipulator of human assets,
他成了眾所周知的海外招募專家 （中情局經常收買招募海外人員提供情報）
and he literally rewrote Agency interrogation protocols.
而且他完全改寫了情報局審訊程序
Frost served in many active theaters,
弗羅斯特在許多活躍地區都任職過
including Libya from 1995 to 1998,
包括1995至1998年的利比亞
Jordan, 1998 to 2000.
1998年至2000年的約旦
During his tenure in Jordan,
他在約旦任職期間
Frost was suspected of leaking information to Mossad,
弗羅斯特被懷疑洩露情報給摩薩德
but nothing was confirmed.
但是完全無法證實
Ten years ago,Frost went off the reservation completely.
10年前，弗羅斯特徹底離開情報局
He currentIy has no allegiances
他現在並不忠誠於美國
and is wanted for espionage on four continents.
因在四大洲進行間諜活動被通緝
His last known sighting is Hamburg, Germany, in 2011 .
他最後一次露面是在德國漢堡，2011年
You know, Harlan,we should interrogate Frost now.
你知道，哈蘭，我們該馬上審訊弗羅斯特
Sweat him for everything he's got.
讓他招出所有知道的事
Once he's stateside,we have fewer options.
一旦他回國，我們就沒什麼手段了
I have an interrogator in Yemen,can be there in eight hours.
我在也門有個審訊官，8小時內就能到那兒
I already have a team in Jo'burg that can be there in two.
我在約翰內斯堡有隊人馬，2小時內就能到
We'll take Frost to the safe house,interrogate him there.
我們會把弗羅斯特帶到安全屋，在那兒審訊他
My people are fully capable of handling this.
我的人完全能應付這事
This is Tobin Frost.
這可是托賓·弗羅斯特
We'll go with Jo'burg.
派約翰內斯堡的人去吧
Okay.
好的
You must turn around.
你必須改變意見
Help. Help.
救命，救命啊
Accident.
我要機遇
Housekeeping.
「客房服務」
We have a last-minute reservation.
我們有個「最後一分鐘預訂」 （還是酒店用語）
ETA for check-in?
預計「入住時間」呢？
Sometime tonight.Freeark Insurance.
今晚某個時候，是「福利亞克保險公司」
Got it.
收到
Hello. Hey.
- 你好 - 嘿
Hey, where are you?
嘿，你在哪兒？
Parker just handed me his oversight papers to finish
帕克剛把他漏掉的文件交給我完成
and his daughter Chloe's got the measles,can you believe that?
而且他女兒克洛伊得了麻疹，你能相信嗎？
How long are you going to be out for?
你要在外面待多久？
I don't know. I don't know.
我不知道，我不知道
Okay. Well, look,I'm gonna dive into this,
好的，額，聽著，我要處理下文件
and then hopefully I can meet up with you later, okay?
但願稍後我能跟你碰面，好嗎？
Yeah, that sounds good.
好的，聽起來不錯
Hey, hey. . .
嘿，嘿
I love you.
我愛你
I love you, too.
我也愛你
Bye.abcBye.
- 再見
Extraction team is in the air, sir.
撤離隊伍起飛了，長官
They should be on the ground within the hour.
他們應該一小時內就能落地了
I want that team in and out of the city in less than 1 2 hours.
我要求隊伍不得在城內逗留超過12小時
We're not even supposed to have
我們甚至不能
a presence in Cape Town. Yes, sir.
- 在開普敦留下蹤跡 - 是，長官
Any communications about Frost's whereabouts are strictIy need-to-know.
任何有關弗羅斯特下落的信息都要嚴格掌握
Sir, the extraction team is en route to the consulate now.
長官，撤離隊伍正前往領事館
Who's reaching out to 7-R?
誰負責跟7-R號聯繫？
Richards, ma'am.
是我，理查茲，女士
I want the housekeeper briefed.
通知「管理員」
High-priority target is coming in.I want the house quiet.
高級別目標正要進駐，要保證房子絕對安全
Under no circumstances should there be
任何情況下都不允許
any communication until the team has left.
有任何通訊聯繫直到隊伍離開
Yes, ma'am.
是，女士
Yeah?
喂？
Do you have a room?
還有房間嗎？
Account? Daniel Kiefer.
- 預約名字？ - 丹尼爾·基弗
Freeark lnsurance. K-l-E-F-E-R.
福利亞克保險公司，基--弗
Kiefer. Freeark Insurance. K-l-E-F-E-R.
基弗，福利亞克保險公司，基--弗
You are a go.
允許「入住」
Hi, l'm Weston.Guest room?
嗨，我是韋斯頓，客房呢？
It's right around the corner.Two rights and a left.
拐角處右邊，兩次右轉再左轉
All the way back.
一直走到頭
That's Tobin Frost.
是托賓·弗羅斯特
Stay with him.Let's go download our gear.
盯著他，我們去放下「行李」
Yes, sir.
是，長官
Linen closet?
壁櫥在哪兒？
Down the hall.Just right at the end, there.
那邊，沿著走廊，就在盡頭
Kill all the surveillance cameras in this room.
把這房間的所有監控頭都關了
My name is Daniel Kiefer.
我叫丹尼爾·基弗
We were at The Farm together.
我們曾一起在佩裏營訓練 （The Farm = 中情局訓練基地）
Technically,you were a year ahead.
準確說來，你比我早一年
I'm here to make you aware of your rights.
我是來告知你的權利的
You're being held under a National Security Directive,
你因國家安全令被扣留
which means you have none,but you know that.
這意味著你沒有任何權利，不過你懂的
Six-hundreds.
600克
The towels,you need six-hundreds.
你需要600克的毛巾
Those are 350,375-gram weight.
那些是350,375克重的
You're gonna need six-hundreds.
你需要600克重的
I want to know the reasons for you being in Cape Town.
我想知道你出現在開普敦的理由
I want you to name your resources,contacts, assets,
我要你說出你的情報資源，聯絡人，人手情況
everybody you've done business with,
自你背叛國家以來的九年裏
traded intel with,sold secrets to,
所有跟你做過交易的人
in the nine years since you betrayed your country.
買過情報的，賣過機密的
Absolutely.Anything you want, Daniel.
當然，隨便問，丹尼爾
Khalid Sheikh Mohammed lasted 20 seconds.
哈立德·謝赫·穆罕默德堅持了20秒 （911主謀之一）
They had six-hundreds.
他們用的600克
Is this legal?
這合法嗎？
Bring him down.
把他按倒
Bring him up.
扶他起來
How long was that?
堅持了多久？
All right,take him down.
好吧，按倒他
Bring him up!
扶他起來！
Get me a knife.
給我把刀
Miller?
米勒？
Get in there with Frost.
進去看著弗羅斯特
Sir, all the security cameras are down.
長官，所有安全攝像頭都失效了
Reboot. l want to see what's out there. Copy that.
- 重啟，我要知道外面什麼情況 - 收到
Let's go, boys!
我們走，夥計們！
Go! Go! Go!
走！走！走！
Let's go, move!
我們走，行動！
Velez, take this corner.
維利斯，守住角落
Ericksson,get the back elevator.
埃裏克森，守住備用電梯
Pope, what do you got?
波普，你看到什麼了？
Sir, l see approximately 12 heavily armed men in perimeter two.
長官，我看見兩隊共約12名重型武裝分子
Okay, gents! Work fore to aft.
好的，兄弟們！從前到後佈置人手
Two-by-twos.Perimeter two.
兩人一組，分兩隊
Greer?abc Sir!
- 格裏爾？ - 長官！
Ericksson?abc Yes, sir.
- 埃裏克森？ - 是，長官
Velez?
維利斯？
I'm good !
我準備好了！
Let's go, fellas.
準備交火，夥計們
Incoming !abcGrenade!
- 敵襲！ - 震撼彈！
Greer!
格裏爾！
Step-slide! Start walking back!
貼牆！逐步後撤！
Velez! Three-round bursts!
維利斯！三發點射！
Velez, where's Greer?
維利斯，格裏爾在哪兒？
He's over there, sir.
他在那邊，長官
Go, son.
上，孩子
This ain't a test.This is the real thing.
這不是測試，是玩真的
What are you gonna do?
你要怎麼辦？
You don't want to try me.
你別想支走我
Magazine!abc Let's go.
- 彈夾！ - 我們走
Velez, stay there!
維利斯，待在那兒！
Listen to me,stay there!
聽我說，待在那裏！
Son of a bitch !
狗日的！
Hey! Get in here!
嘿！到裏面來！
Hey, hey. Take these.
嘿，嘿，拿著鑰匙
Go watch him.
去看著他
Hey, they're here for me,but they want me alive.
嘿，他們是來找我的，不過他們想讓我活著
You, they'll kill.
你就死定了
You got one in the chamber?
你槍膛上有子彈嗎？
It's okay.
沒關係
I remember my first posting.Rio de Janeiro.
我記得我首次出任務去里約熱內盧
A house like this.Beautiful women.
房子像這一樣，還有漂亮女人
Not one single visitor,but I remember rule number one.
一個「客人」都沒有，不過我記得第一準則
You are responsible for your houseguest.
你要對你的「房客」負責
I'm your houseguest.
我就是你的「房客」
The clock is ticking.They gave you the keys.
時間緊迫，他們給你鑰匙了
Do your duty, son.
負起責任來，孩子
Shut up. Let me think.
閉嘴，讓我想想
You want to be the guy that lost Tobin Frost?
你想要當丟失托賓·福羅斯熱的人？
Tick-tock, tick-tock, tick-tock.
嘀嗒-嘀嗒-嘀嗒
Where's Frost?
弗羅斯特在哪裏？
We're leaving.
我們離開這兒
Where is he?
他在哪裏？
Stay here, stay here!Wait! Don't move!
待在這兒，待在這兒！等等！別動！
Hey, hey, hey!
嘿，嘿，嘿！
Go!
上！
Get in the trunk.
進後備箱
Are you serious?Yeah, get in.
- 你說真的？ - 是的，進去
The trunk?Get in the trunk now!
- 後備箱？ - 馬上進後備箱！
No!
不！
Ops Center.
行動中心
Echo Three Victor Echo Nine.
E-3-V-E-9
Go ahead.
請說
This is Weston.7-R's been hit.Everyone's dead.
我是韋斯頓，7-R號遭遇襲擊，所有人都死了
I need you to repeat that, pIease.Say again.
我需要你重複一遍，再說一次
Kiefer,his team, everyone,they're all dead.
基弗，他的隊伍，所有人，他們都死了
Stand by.
稍等
Transferring.
中轉中
lt's the house.
是安全屋打來的
Linklater. This is Weston.
- 我是林克萊特 - 我是韋斯頓
The safe house has been breached.
安全屋遭人闖入
What's your location?
你的方位？
I'm eastbound on Albert Road.
我正在艾伯特公路上向東行駛
I'm just passing woodstock.
我剛剛經過伍德斯托克
I want eyes on this.Real-time sat feed.
我要實時衛星傳送圖像
LINKLATER: And what's the location of the guest?
「房客」的位置呢？
We escaped.
我們脫逃了
Clarify.Do you have the guest?
說清楚些，你帶著「房客」嗎？
Yes, we escaped !
是的，我們脫逃了！
Look, I can make it to the consulate.
聽著，我可以趕到領事館
There's no chance for SDR,
無法執行反追蹤
I think I might have picked up a tail.
我想我正被人追殺
We can't have a gun battle in front of the consulate.
我們不能在領事館前開槍
Diplomatic catastrophe.
會引發外交災難的
Where's that satellite feed?
衛星圖像在哪裏？
Denied by National Recon.War theater use only.
被國家偵察局否決了，說是只能在戰區使用
Buy us some time.
給我們爭取點時間
Do not go to the consulate.
別去領事館
Follow protocol Alpha Zero.
照A0號程序做
Secure the guest and stay off the grid.
保護」房客「，不要上網
Reconnect at 1800 hours.I repeat, stay off the grid.
下午18:00再聯絡，我重複一次，不要上網
Copy, copy, copy.
收到，收到，收到
All right,Cape Town police have responded to the house.
好的，開普敦警方已經去安全屋了
Confirmed.abc I want the site secured.
- 確認了 - 我要保證房子安全
I'm hearing nine dead.
我聽到死亡9人
Initiating damage control.
啟動損失控制預案
I'm on it.Reaching out to NIA now.
我正在做，同國家情報局聯繫中
The locals are going to have that house locked off.
當地警察會把房子封鎖起來
Check all the traffic cameras,police reports...
檢查所有的交通監控頭，警方報告...
Find out why Frost wanted to go in that consulate to begin with
找出一開始為什麼弗羅斯特要走進領事館
and who in the hell else might be after him.
以及到底可能還有誰在找他
We need to get Weston and Frost out of South Africa.
我們要把韋斯頓和弗羅斯特接出南非
Now, do we have any tactical teams?Anything in play?
目前我們還有行動隊嗎？有活著的嗎？
Yeah, l have assets in Egypt,but they're in deep.
是的，我在埃及有人手，但是他們藏得很深
If I pull them out,that would compromise two years' worth of work.
如果我把他們派出去，那就會白費兩年情報工作
I can scramble a team from Europe or Asia,
我能從歐洲或亞洲緊急調人
but it's going to take at least 18 hours.
不過這需要至少18小時
At this point,Weston is all we got.
當前我們只能靠韋斯頓了 （你可是中央情報局啊。。。）
I need to find out who this Matt Weston is,right now.
我要馬上知道馬特·韋斯頓是誰
Matthew James Weston.
馬修·詹姆士·韋斯頓
Born 02-24-82 to Terry and Madeline weston
1982年2月24日出生，父母是特裏和馬德琳·韋斯頓
in Port washington,New York.
出生於華盛頓港，紐約人
An assault arrest,one month after
就在父母和妹妹
both parents and a younger sister
因父親血液酒精含量
were killed in a traffic accident
兩倍於法定限制
in which his father's blood-alcohol
而發生交通意外去世一個月後
was twice the legal limit.
他因襲擊案被捕
Yale, degree in Economics,recruited out of Yale law.
獲得耶魯經濟學學士學位，招募於攻讀耶魯法學專業期間
High marks in analytics and linguistics at The Farm.
受訓期間在分析學和語言學方面取得高分
Excellent in tradecraft skills.
諜報技術能力優秀
His girlfriend, Ana Moreau,is a French national.
他的女友，安娜·莫羅 是法國人
He reported them as having "close and continuing contact."
他匯報說「他們關係親密長久」
She's a second year resident in the oncology department at Groote Schuur.
她已在格魯特舒爾醫院腫瘤部做了兩年醫生
Get in that car.
進車裏去
She accepted a position with Hotel-Dieu Hospital
她兩周後就要調往
in Paris,starts in two weeks.
巴黎的主宮醫院 （教會辦的醫院）
No known political affiliations. She's clean.
沒有任何政治聯繫，她沒問題
I want you to post a car outside their apartment.
我要你在他們公寓外佈置車輛
Use back channels.
利用備用渠道
And get NSA to cross-check their telephone records and their e-mails, please.
讓國家安全局覆核下他們的電話記錄和電子郵件
Yes, ma'am.
是，長官
FROST: You know, it would be easier if I knew where we were going.
你知道，如果我知道我們要去哪兒事情就好辦多了
You just drive, all right?Just drive, middle lane.
你只管開車，好嗎？只管開在中間車道
All right.
好的
Hey, what are you doing?Middle lane.
嘿，你在幹嘛？中間車道
Just drive around.
只管到處開
All right.I'm driving.
好吧，我開著呢
Nice to know who you're talking to.What's your name?
很高興知道你在跟誰說話，你叫什麼？
You crushed my windpipe.
你壓壞我的氣管了
Well, you locked me in the trunk.
誰讓你把我鎖在後備箱
Come on, you're not NOC.You're here under your real name.
說啊，你又不是非官方臥底，是用真名行事的
What is it?
叫什麼？
Weston, Matt.
韋斯頓，馬特
All right.
好的
How long you been a safe house keeper?
你做安全屋管理人多久了？
Twelve months.
12個月
Happy birthday.
週年快樂
Cape Town,that's low-level detail.
開普敦是個低級別事務區
You should have been out of here by now.
你現在該已經離開這兒了
Maybe I requested the assignment.
沒準是我要求出任務
Or maybe Langley doesn't trust you with anything else.
或者可能蘭利不相信你能勝任別的事
So, what's your plan?
那你的計劃是什麼？
Oh, let me guess.Follow protocol.
哦，我猜猜看，遵照程序
Protocol states that if your house is crashed,
程序上說如果你的房子暴露了
you do an SDR to make sure no one's following you.
你得反追蹤以確保沒人跟蹤你
Activate your GPS in your Go-Bag,select another safe house.
使用你衝鋒包裏的GPS，選擇下一處安全屋
You think I'm going to let you just take me in?
你以為我會就這樣任你擺佈？
I think you need to shut up.
我覺得你該閉嘴了
I think you need to consider how your house was attacked in the first place.
我覺得你該想想一開始為什麼你的房子會遭襲
Have you done that, Matt?
你想過沒，馬特？
They followed Kiefer.They followed him from the consulate,
他們跟蹤基弗，從領事館一路跟來
and that's how they found the safe house.
他們就是這樣找到安全屋的
Come on, you don't really believe that,do you?
拜託，你不會真的相信這個吧？
How did they know l was near the consulate in the first place?
他們一開始怎麼會知道我在領事館附近？
Hmm.
嗯
But l like this, you know.You and me, figuring shit out.
不過我喜歡，你知道嗎，你和我，患難與共
Like the Hardy Boys.
就好像哈迪兄弟 （職業摔角雙打組合）
That house was a secure location.
那所房子位置機密
Whoever crashed it
不管是誰發現的
didn't stop by a gas station and ask for directions to the nearest safe house.
肯定不是停在加油站直接問最近安全屋的方位那麼簡單
They were invited.Someone told them,Matthew.
他們是被引過去的，有人告密，馬修
Think about it.Someone you know.
想想吧，是你認識的人
So you better ask yourself,can you trust your landlord?
所以你最好問問自己，你能信任你的「老闆」嗎？
Go ahead,you're not going to get in my head.
隨你說，反正你沒法動搖我
I already am in your head.
我已經動搖你了
They're going to isolate you, Matt.
他們要孤立你，馬特
They're going to be real nice to you at first.
起初他們會對你很好
They're going to put their arm around you and tell you things like,
他們會把手搭你肩上，跟你說什麼
"You did a decent job, son.We'll take it from here."
「你幹得很好，孩子，我們在此交接吧」
That's when you know you're screwed.
那時候你就知道你被耍了
Forget about me.They're going to focus on you.
別管我了，他們會全力盯著你
They're going to try and make a connection between you and I.
他們會試著在你我之間建立聯繫
So that if this all goes wrong,
這樣如果事情搞砸了
they'll have something to fall back on
他們在參議院聽證會上
in their little Senate hearings.
就有理由推脫了
I'm not your only enemy tonight.
今晚我不是你唯一的敵人
So, it's someone in-house.
看來局裏有內奸
It's the only way this thing could've heppen
這是發生這種事的唯一合理解釋
We were completely buttoned up.
我們肯定守口如瓶
I want a list of everyone who knew about this.
我要一份所有瞭解內幕的人員名單
Backgrounds, affiliations,
背景資料，社會關係
particularly any connections with Frost.
特別是跟弗羅斯特的關係
Every movement right up until this operation.
此次行動以前的一舉一動都要知道
Your extraction team,how long had they been together?
你的撤離隊伍，他們組隊多久了？
My team had been together six months.Why?
我的人在一起6個月了，怎麼？
Well, I'm just trying to get my head around this.
好吧，我就從這裏著手調查
That will do, thank you.
那行，謝謝
Hello. Hey.
- 你好 - 嘿
Baby, where are you?
寶貝，你在哪裏？
I'm all right.I'm okay.
我沒事，我很好
I'm okay.
我很好
I'm sorry I didn't call you back,I saw your missed calls.
對不起我沒回你電話，我看到未接來電了
You must be worried sick.
你肯定擔心死了
Is everything okay?
一切順利嗎？
I'm good.I'm good. Listen.
我很好，我很好，聽著
This sounds so crazy.
這聽起來很瘋狂
We had some threats against the clinic last night,
我們昨晚在診所遭遇恐嚇
so Parker and I,we stayed all night
帕克和我，我們待了一整晚
trying to get to the bottom of it.
試圖弄清楚怎麼回事
And I'm sorry that I didn't call you back.I should have, right away.
我很抱歉，沒有回你電話，我本該及時回復的
I was so worried.
我好擔心
I know.
我知道
Can you do me a favor?Can you go over to the window for a second?
你能幫個忙嗎？你能到窗戶那兒去一下嗎？
why?
為什麼？
Can you just take a quick look out the window?
你能瞄一眼窗外嗎？
I want you to see if there's anyone out there.
我要你看看外面是否有人
Are there any cars that don't belong?
是否有什麼外來車輛？
Anyone hanging around out front?
車前面有什麼人在徘徊嗎？
There's a police car.
有輛警車
what's going on?
怎麼回事？
I'm sorry about this.
對不起
I know this is a lot,
我知道這有點過分
but we felt like it would be best
但是我們覺得為以防萬一
if we didn't go home as a precaution,
我們最好不回家
and I agree with him.
我同意他的意見
I know there's nothing to worry about,but I agree with him.
我知道沒什麼可擔心的，不過我同意他的意見
I think you should just go to Dena's for a little while,
我認為你應該去蒂娜家待段時間
just for a few hours,and I'll call you in a little bit.
就待幾個小時，稍後我會跟你聯繫
And we'll get together, okay?
然後我們碰面，好嗎？
Okay, I'll go.
好的，我會去的
Okay. I love you.I'll talk to you soon,all right?
好的，我愛你，我待會打給你，好嗎？
Don't worry. Okay, bye.
別擔心，好的，再見
She know what you do for a living?
她知道你是幹什麼的？
The girl on the phone.It was a girl, wasn't it?
電話裏的女生，是女生，對吧？
Maybe it was a guy,I don't know.
沒準是個男的，我不知道
I don't judge.
我不做評論
You can't expect to have a real relationship in our line of work, Matthew.
幹我們這行你不能指望有真感情，馬修
Don't worry.She's not going to leave you.
別擔心，她不會離開你的
See, what happens is,you try to protect her with lies,
懂嗎，事實是，你試圖用謊言來保護她
and then it starts to add up.
然後謊言逐漸成真了
At the safe house you said that they'd kill me to get to you.
在安全屋你說他們為了抓你會殺了我
After a while,even the truth. . .
後來，即使真相...
Why? . . .starts to sound like a lie.
- 為什麼？ - 也聽起來像是謊言
You have something. You got something that they want.What is it?
你有東西，你有他們要的東西，是什麼？
Is she a local?
她是本地的嗎？
Don't worry about her.What is it?
別管她，是什麼？
Oh, it is a girl.
哦，看來是女生啊
You'll keep covering your tracks,she'll keep believing.
你會繼續掩蓋你的身份，她則會繼續相信
Because she wants to, because she needs to.
因為她想相信，因為她需要相信
That's why we exist,you and me,that's our job.
這就是我們存在的理由，你和我，這是我們的工作
To take advantage of that.
要利用這點
People's desire to believe.
人們渴望相信
To trust.
渴望信任
She's not going to leave you, Matthew.
她不會離開你，馬修
You're going to leave her.
你會離開她
I'm not you.
我不是你
Correct, sir.We verified it.
對的，長官，我們已證實了
That is your boy.You take it.
那是你的人，你來接
Everybody, stand by.
所有人準備
Matty, it's me.
馬特，是我
How are you holding up?
你情況如何？
I'm all right.
我沒事
Matt, we can't get another team in for at least 1 2 hours.
馬特，至少12小時內我們都沒法另派一隊人馬
Sorry.
抱歉
We've cleared a new safe house for you outside the city.
我們在市區外幫你開闢了一棟新安全屋
There's a Go-Bag located
有個衝鋒包放在
at locker number 256,Green Point Stadium Metrorail station.
綠點球場地鐵站256號寄物櫃
The combination is 2-5-1-22.
密碼是25122
2-5-1 -22.
2-5-1-22. 2-5-1-2-2
Now, the bag's got a GPS in it.
包裏有個GPS
It'll direct you to the safe house.
它會指引你前往安全屋
But you got to be careful,it's an active location.
但是你必須小心，這是個「活動點」
So, approach with caution.
所以小心行事
Matt?
馬特？
Do you know how they found Frost?
你知道他們怎麼找到弗羅斯特的嗎？
Do you know who led them to us?
你知道誰把他們引來的嗎？
We're working on that.
我們正在查
We're counting on you, Matt.
我們靠你了，馬特
Get Frost to that safe house and you can write your own ticket.
帶弗羅斯特去安全屋，你就能自行決定去留了
I will.
我會的
Left at the light.
左邊亮燈的地方
To the stadium?
去球場？
Yeah.
是的
Hey, scarf.How much for a scarf?
嘿，圍巾，一條圍巾多少錢？
Only fifty rand.
只要50南非蘭特
Thanks.
謝謝
Cuff your hands together.
把你雙手銬一起
Together? Yeah.
- 一起？ - 是的
Out.
下車
Are you sure you don't want to just walk away from this?
你確定你不想就一走了之？
Can't do that.
辦不到
Yes, you can.You should.
你行的，你應該這樣
Move. Go.Across the street.
走，過去，街對面
Going to the game.I like games.
去看比賽，我喜歡比賽
Metrorail,straight ahead.
下地鐵，直走
Straight ahead.
直走
Right over there.
去那邊
Let's go.
我們走
Help! Help!He's trying to kidnap me!
救命！救命！他想綁架我！
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
哇哦，哇哦，哇哦，哇哦！
He's trying to kidnap me! Help!
他想綁架我！救命！
He's got a gun !
他有槍！
He's got a gun! He's got a gun right there!
他有槍！他手上有槍！
I'm undercover.I'm undercover!
我是臥底，我是臥底！
Calm down, sir.Everybody, calm down !
冷靜，先生，所有人冷靜！
Get down ! Get down !
趴下！趴下！
All right! Okay!
好的！好的！
Get him up. Get up.
扶他起來，起來
Ow, ow, ow!
噢，噢，噢！
I'm an American citizen.I don't know what he wanted from me.
我是美國公民，我不知道他想對我幹嘛
Just calm down.
冷靜
Hey, hey, hey.I'm a police officer.I'm from America.
嘿，嘿，嘿，我是警察，我來自美國
I arrested this man.His name is Tobin Frost.
我拘捕了那個男人，他叫托賓·弗羅斯特
Where did you take him?
你帶他去哪裏了？
He's in the infirmary.
他在醫務室
There, there! Is that it?
那兒，那兒！是那個嗎？
Top left,second screen from the top! Look, look, the infirmary.
左上角，上面往下第二個顯示屏，你看，你看，醫務室
Right. Go back.
好的，快退
Third-tier infirmary,now! Move!
三層醫務室，快！行動！
Third-tier infirmary.Go, now!
三層醫務室，快走！
Do you see?
你看見沒？
Don't move.
別動
Frost!
弗羅斯特！
Hey!
嘿！
Stop! Stop!
站住！站住！
Get out the way!
讓開！
Stop!
站住！
No! Stop!
不！站住！
Medic!
醫生！
Drop the gun.
把槍放下
Drop it.
放下槍
I'm responsible for you.
我要對你負責
You're responsible for yourself.
你要對自己負責
Get on your knees.
跪下
Are you going to kill me?
你要殺了我嗎？
I only kill professionals.
我只殺內行人士
Height,approximateIy six feet.
身高大約6英尺
Anglo, wearing a stadium security jacket.
美國人，穿著球場保安制服
The suspect was last seen entering Green Point Stadium Metrorail,
嫌犯最後現身進入綠點球場地鐵站
stadium concourse.
即球場大廳
Sir, we have a thread on what Frost might be doing in Cape Town.
長官，我們有弗羅斯特為何現身開普敦的線索了
Can you bring up. . .
你能調出...
Alec Wade.Fifteen-year NOC at MI6.
亞力克·韋德，軍情六局做了15年非官方臥底
Sabotage, counter-ambush,counter-IED tactics,
破壞，反狙擊，反簡易爆炸裝置
until he blew up an op in Lisbon four years ago
直到他四年前在里斯本搞砸了一項任務 （葡萄牙首都）
and was put on a desk,pushing papers.
接著被安排轉做文職
Cape Town Police found him shot through the head,
開普敦警方發現他頭部中槍
high-powered rifle,1 4 blocks from the consulate.
用的大威力步槍，距領事館14街區
Witnesses placed someone fitting Frost's description
目擊者對槍擊發生時車內人員的描述
in the car at the time of the shooting.
符合弗羅斯特的特徵
And we think, what?That they were working together?
那我們的結論是什麼？他們是同夥？
They ran joint operations in Hamburg in the mid-'80s.
80年代中期他們在漢堡執行過聯合行動
Frost's last sighting was in Hamburg, 201 1 .
弗羅斯特上次現身是在2011年的漢堡
And what are the Brits saying about Wade?
英國方面對韋德有何說法？
Officially,they're saying nothing.
官方層面，他們什麼都沒說
Unofficially?
非官方呢？
He's been the subject of a five-month internal investigation.
他已經接受了5個月的內部調查
They think he's been trading intel.
他們認為他在出賣情報
Hmm.
嗯
So what the hell did Wade leak to Frost
那麼韋德到底給弗羅斯特洩露了什麼
that was so important it was worth killing six of our men?
重要到值得幹掉我們6個人？
I want more details from MI6.Call in every chit you got.
我要更多軍情六局的細節，動用你所有渠道
Yes, sir.
是，長官
David, I want an internal investigation
大衛，我要進行一次內部調查
into Daniel Kiefer and his team.
關於丹尼爾·基弗和他手下的
I've got Weston calling in for David Barlow.
我這邊接到韋斯頓找大衛·巴洛的電話
I lost him.
我跟丟了他
Frost?
弗羅斯特？
Yeah, he's gone.
是的，他不見了
After I picked up the GPS,he created a diversion,
在我拿到GPS後，他故意製造混亂
took out a couple of cops at the stadium.
打死了兩個球場警察
BARLOW: Any idea where he's headed?
知道他去哪裏了嗎？
Not exactly,but I will.
不清楚，但是我會找到的
This is Linklater.You said he took out two cops?
我是林克萊特，你說他幹掉兩個警察？
Matt, you're on speaker.
馬特，把你接到喇叭上了
Yes, ma'am.At the Green Point Stadium.
是的，女士，在綠點球場
involvement in a possibIe kidnapping.
...牽涉一起疑似綁架案
The suspect is being described as a white male of medium build.
據稱嫌犯是一名中等身材白種男子
Stadium police is reporting you shot a cop.
球場警察說是你打死的
I returned fire in self-defense.
我出於自衛才開火的
The fact of the matter is,Frost is on the loose.
事實情況是：弗羅斯特跑了
I've spent the last 1 4 hours with him.
14小時以來我一直跟他在一起
He might have said or done something that could lead me to him.
他也許說了或做了什麼可以幫我找到他的事
You are to stand down,proceed to the consulate,
你撤退前往領事館
and present yourself for exfil and debrief.Acknowledge.
表明自己是撤下來匯報情況的，明白嗎
By the time I'm debriefed,Frost will be gone.
在我匯報情況時，弗羅斯特會跑掉的
I've spent 12 months researching
我已經花了12個月研究
every square inch of this town.
這城市的每寸土地
I will find Frost and I'll deliver him.
我會找到弗羅斯特並把他交出來的
Weston, this is Harlan Whitford, son.
韋斯頓，我是哈蘭·威特福德，孩子
Now, you've done a fine job,but we'll take it from here.
目前你都做得很好，但是我們在此交接吧
Understood.
明白
Hello.
你好
Sir, I respectfully request that,
長官，我懇請
that exchange not make it onto his files.
這次交接不要寫入他的檔案
He's either incompetent or he's working with somebody else.
他要麼無能要麼是跟別人串謀
Do not make this about Weston.
別這樣評論韋斯頓
It was your guys that lost Frost.
是你的人弄丟了弗羅斯特
It was your team that folded at the safe house.
是你的人馬在安全屋搞砸了
I want both of you on an airplane to Cape Town.
我要你們都飛去開普敦
Frost is trying to get out of the country.Go find his ass.
弗羅斯特正試圖離開南非，把他找回來
There you go, baby.
就是你，寶貝
One ticket to Jo'burg.
一張去約翰內斯堡的票
Thank you.
謝謝
Police had detained American NGO worker Matthew Weston
作為槍擊案疑似嫌犯，警方曾拘留美籍
as a possible suspect in the shooting.
非政府組織工作人員馬修·韋斯頓
Weston had been detained earlier today,
韋斯頓是今天早些時候被拘留的
but managed to escape while being questioned by stadium security officials
但是在被球場保安訊問關於他
about his involvement in the shootings.
涉嫌槍擊案一事期間設法脫逃
The suspect has been described as a white male of medium build,
據稱嫌犯是一名中等身材白種男子
possibly wearing a stadium security outfit.
可能身穿球場保安制服
Baby.
寶貝
Are you all right?
你沒事吧？
l lied to you.
我對你撒謊了
About everything.The NGO, Parker.
包括所有事，非政府組織，帕克
My job.
我的工作
My family.
我的家庭
So, who do you work for?
那你是為誰工作的？
The government.
政府
CIA.
中情局
No, I don't. . .
不，我沒...
I don't do anything.
我什麼都沒干
I sit around in an apartment all day.I answer the phone.
我只是整天待在公寓接電話
I need you to leave.
我要你離開這裏
I need you to do that for me. Okay?
我要你為我離開，好嗎？
Here.
拿著
This is a ticket to Jo'burg.
這是去約翰內斯堡的票
When you get there,you go straight to the airport.
等你到了那裏，你直接去機場
There's a 6:00 a.m. flight to Paris.
有一趟早上六點去巴黎的航班
Take this.
拿著這個
You take this.If anyone stops you. . .
你拿著這個，如果有誰攔住你...
If anyone stops you. . .If anybody stops you. . .
如果有誰攔住你.. 如果有誰攔住你...
Who do you think I am?
你把我當什麼人了？
Stop, stop.
住手，住手
Fuck you !
操你媽！
Hey, stop. Stop it.
嘿，住手，住手
We broke up a week ago.You haven't seen me since, okay?
我們一周前分手了，從那以後就沒見過我，好嗎？
I'm sorry.
對不起
Just leave. Please?
走吧，好嗎？
Do you love me?
你愛我嗎？
Very much.
非常愛
Go. Go.
走，走
Go.
走
Attention, all passengers,
各位乘客請注意
Platform 20 for Langa Township
20號站台前往蘭加鎮的列車 （南非黑人聚居地）
departing in five minutes.
五分鐘內就要發車了
Langa Township,departing in five minutes.
蘭加鎮五分鐘內發車
Sir. Someone just logged into our system using Weston's password
長官，剛剛有人用韋斯頓的密碼登陸了我們的系統
accessing his stored files.
訪問了他存儲的資料
it's him.What the hell is he doing?
是他，他到底在幹嘛？
I'm not sure.
我不確定
I want to see what he's looking at.
我想知道他在看什麼
He's pulled an old report
他瀏覽了一份老報告
on surveillance targets living in the Langa Township area.
關於住在蘭加鎮區域的監視目標的
It's a profiIe of Carlos Villar,a Nicaraguan national.
這是卡洛斯·維拉的資料，尼加拉瓜人
He's a known document forger.
他是著名的假證專家
Get me a copy of Weston's report.
給我一份韋斯頓報告的副本
Yes, sir.
是，長官
Logged off, sir.He's gone.
退出登錄，長官，他離開了
An Internet cafe on Long Street.
地址是長街一家網絡咖啡屋
Like a black Dorian Gray.
簡直是黑人版道林·格雷 （參閱2009年的《道林·格雷》）
That's right.How you doing, brother?
說得對，你怎麼樣，兄弟？
Come in. Yes, sir.
- 請進 - 好的，先生
Illana?
伊蘭娜？
Hi.
嗨
We have a guest.
我們有客人了
Illana.Good to meet you.
- 伊蘭娜 - 很高興見到你
Joseph, my daughter.
約瑟芬，我女兒
How are you? Hello.
- 你好嗎？ - 你好
My son-in-law.
我女婿
May I offer you some tea?
你要喝點茶嗎？
No, we're going upstairs.
不，我們上樓去了
I remembered.
我曾記得
You even let it breathe.
你常掛在嘴邊
"Too long a sacrifice Can make a stone of the heart
「太長久的犧牲能把心變為一塊岩石 」
"O when may it suffice?
「呵，什麼時候才算個夠？」
"That is Heaven's part"
「那是天的事」 （愛爾蘭詩人葉芝《1916年復活節》）
In the old days,a cheap bottle
過去一瓶便宜的佛羅迪康納酒
of Flor de Cana kept us happy all night.
就能讓我們快活一整晚
Mmm. Tastes change.
嗯，口味變了
People change.
人變了
People don't change.
人不會變
We grow old.
是我們老了
And some of us adapt.
我們身體適應了
And learn how to enjoy simple pleasures of life,
學會如何享受生活中的簡單快樂
like a family, a home.
比如家人，家庭
And for you. . .
至於你...
What's in that glass right now, for you,
現在對你來說杯子裏裝的
is as good as it's ever going to be.
就和從前一樣好味道
One day you'll understand.
有一天你會理解的
You got more past than future, you learn.
等你餘生不多時，你就懂了
What is this? An intervention?
這算什麼？干涉我的生活？
I thought you were dead.
我以為你死了
So, what brings you to my home in the middle of the night
多年以後，什麼風把你
after all these years?
半夜吹到我家來了？
Ooh.
哦
Papa?
爸爸？
Uh-huh.
啊哈
We're going.
我們要走了
Okay, be careful.
好的，小心點
Okay, Papa.
好的，爸爸
What are you going to do with this?
你要怎麼處理這個？
Make some money.
賺錢
Let me borrow your glasses.
借我眼鏡用用
That's it. Listen.
就是這個，聽著
I'm going to need a new passport,photo lD, driver's license,
我需要一張新護照，帶照片的證件，駕照
the whole shebang.Can you do that for me?
全套家當，你能幫我弄到嗎？
Yeah.
可以
You sure?
你肯定？
Yes.
是的
Weston never showed at the consulate.
韋斯頓沒去領事館
And he was just accessing our secure server,
而且他剛訪問了我們的安全服務器
searching for someone to create an alias package.
想找人辦假證
He's trying to leave the country.
他正試圖離開南非
Or he's going after Frost.
或者他要去抓弗羅斯特
Look at what happened at the soccer stadium.
看看足球場的情況
This guy let Frost escape.
這傢伙放跑了弗羅斯特
I think Weston's turned.
我認為韋斯頓叛變了
I know this boy.
我瞭解這人
He's been Iooking for a chance to prove himseIf.
他正尋找機會證明自己
He's trying to bring in Frost.
他正試圖追捕弗羅斯特
Come on, David.
得了吧，大衛
You're not seeing the evidence.
你不看證據麼
Not my best work.
不是我最好的作品
But given the pressure of time, it's passable.
不過鑒於時間緊迫，還行
It's good.I'll wire you the money
很好，一離開城鎮
as soon as I get out of town.
我就把錢匯給你
Tobin, don't do this.It's different.
托賓，別這樣做，情況不同
You don't need the trouble, you don't need the money.
你別惹麻煩，別只顧賺錢
You can give it. . .
你可以把它交給...
Carlos!
卡洛斯！
Illana!
伊蘭娜！
Carlos.
卡洛斯
Carlos!
卡洛斯！
Go.
走
He's on the roof!
他在屋頂！
Go! Go!
上！上！
Get in the car!
上車！
They think they can come at me like this.
他們以為這樣就能抓到我
Have to do it a whole lot better than that.
還得再計劃周密點
Shit!
該死！
Matt, how'd you find me?
馬特，你怎麼找到我的？
It wasn't that hard.
這並不困難
Let's go.
我們走
Wait, wait, wait.
等等，等等，等等
Who do you work for?
你為誰工作？
Who sent you?
誰派你來的？
Who sent you? Who sent you?
誰派你來的？誰派你來的？
Who?
誰？
Vargas.
瓦格斯
Who's Vargas?
瓦格斯是誰？
You want to die?
你想死嗎？
Matt.
馬特
CIA.
中情局
CIA! CIA!
中情局！中情局！
Report?
情況報告呢？
There was a shootout in the Langa Township.
蘭加鎮發生槍戰
Two crime scenes.One at the residence of Carlos Villar.
有兩處案發點，一處在卡洛斯·維拉的住處
He's a document forger.
他是個假證專家
The other in a nearby tenement.
另一處在附近房子裏
And where was Frost last seen?
弗羅斯特最後現身地點呢？
Tenement.
第二案發點
Have fun at Villar's.
祝你維拉家調查順利
We'll meet up later.
我們稍後碰面
You were right about Ana.
關於安娜你說得對
That's her name.
那是她的名字
Sorry to hear that.
很遺憾聽到這些
Most case officers get married three,four times.
大部分案件官員都會結三四次婚 （中情局兩類工作人員之一）
You?
你呢？
Once.
一次
You're falling apart over here.
你這裏有傷
Don't kill innocent people,Matthew.
別殺無辜的人，馬修
What?
什麼？
Air traffic controller,a tiny airstrip in Bermuda.
空管員，負責百慕大群島一條小跑道
George Edwart Cox,I remember that name.
喬治·愛德華特·考克斯，我記得那個名字
Edwart, with a "T."
愛德華特，名字裏帶個T
My inside officer said he was organizing arms shipments,
我的上司說他負責武器運輸
but he was just an air traffic controller.He was just a guy.
但是他只是個空管員，是個普通人
I put a bullet in his skull.
我開槍打中了他的頭
Black Ops came in,they replaced him with one of their own,
事情成了黑色行動，他們用自己人替換了他
and crashed a Gulfstream in the ocean that night.
然後當晚偽裝成海上飛機失事
The thing was,the family that was on the plane. . .
事實是，機上的那家人
The husband,he was a whistleblower.
那個丈夫，他是個證人
The whole thing was about
整件事只是為了
stopping him from testifying about wet works
阻止他出席國會聽證會
to a congressional hearing.
指證暗殺行動
Is that why you left?
這就是你離開的原因？
No.
不
I went back to work the next day like nothing ever happened.
第二天我當做什麼都沒發生去上班
You practice anything a long time,you get good at it.
你某件事做久了，就會熟能生巧
You tell a hundred lies a day,it sounds like the truth.
你一天撒一百次謊，聽起來就成真了
Everyone betrays everyone.
人人互相背叛
That's a shitty excuse.
這借口真拙劣
Yeah, I used to be innocent like you.
是啊，我也曾像你這樣天真
Wrap myself up in the flag. . .
想要馬革裹屍...
I'm going to take you in.
我要逮捕你
Good for you.
好樣的
Barlow.
巴洛
Witnesses identified a pair of men
目擊者認出了兩個人
fitting weston and Frost's description
均符合韋斯頓和弗羅斯特的特徵
leaving this location together.
他們一起離開的
So, he pulled it off.
看來他成功了
Weston is aiding and abetting a fugitive.
韋斯頓正協助支持一名逃犯
You're wrong.
你錯了
If he's with Frost,he's taking him to the safe house.
如果他跟弗羅斯特在一起，他就會帶他到安全屋
That's where we got to be.
那就是我們要去的地方
Fine. Fine.
好吧，好吧
Meet me at the crossroads at Old Malmesbury Road.
跟我在舊馬姆斯伯裏路的十字路口碰面
Who are you?
你是誰？
You Weston?
你是韋斯頓？
Give me the shotgun.
把霰彈槍給我
What the hell is this?
到底什麼意思？
Who are you?
你是誰？
l'm Keller.Safe house keeper.
我是凱勒，安全屋管理人
Authorization lndex,Bravo Four Seven Oscar Whiskey Six.
授權密碼I-B-4-7-O-W-6
lnside. Let's go.
進去，我們走
To the left.
左邊
Slowly.
慢點
l don't know who trained you, man,but this sure as hell
我不知道誰訓練你的，夥計，不過這肯定
ain't protocol.Where's the guest room?
不是程序，「客房」在哪裏？
That's the thing,we don't really have one.
就這些了，我們沒有真正的「客房」
ln there. ln there.
進去，進去
Cuff him.To the pipe.
把他銬到管子上
Out. Over there.
出去，那邊
All right.
好的
Control room.
控制室
Whatever you say, man.lt's your rodeo.
照你吩咐，夥計，反正是你幹的
Call it in.Let me hear it.
打電話，要讓我聽到
LandIord.
我是「老闆」
My guest is here.
我的「客人」到了
Account?
預約名字？
Abaresque Limited.
埃博拉斯克有限公司
with a guest?
帶「客人」了嗎？
Yeah, package delivered.
是的，目標已送到
Confirmed.Pickup scheduIed.
確認，執行預定計劃
They're on the way.
他們來了
Can we at least put the gun down now?
現在我們至少能放下槍嗎？
Thanks, Clayton. Bye.
謝謝，克萊頓，再見
lt's a microchip.
是個微芯片
What?
什麼？
That was my guy from Ml6.
剛才是我在軍情六局的人
Wade got his hands on a microchip.
韋德拿到了一個微芯片
And what was on it?
裏面有什麼？
Only Wade knew,
只有韋德知道
but l think it's safe to assume
不過我想這就可以合理推斷
that's why he hooked up with Frost.
為何他會跟弗羅斯特聯繫
To sell it.
是為了賣掉它
Let's get moving.
我們走吧
Long day, huh?
漫長的一天，是吧？
l can only imagine.Tobin Frost.
我只能靠想像，托賓·弗羅斯特
That man's a legend.
這傢伙就是個傳奇
l hope you picked up something.
我希望你學到了什麼
You ain't going to find a better education.
你不會再有更好的實踐經歷了
This is the most excitement l've seen.
這是我見過最令人興奮的事了
You're the first guest l've had in 1 0 months.
你是我10個月以來第一個「房客」
But you wouldn't know anything about that, right?
但是你根本不會明白，對吧？
You got a city posting.
你被分配到城市
Yeah, nightlife, beaches.
是的，夜生活，海灘
Little ladies running around everywhere.
到處都是美女
Yeah.
是啊
l'm jealous.
我很妒忌
You got coffee?
你有咖啡嗎？
Yeah, it's in the cupboard.
有，在櫥櫃裏
Where?
哪裏？
Want me to get it? l got it.
- 要我去拿嗎？ - 我去吧
Why are you in Cape Town?
你為什麼來開普敦？
Tell me now. Why?
馬上告訴我，為什麼？
What is it?
什麼東西？
A dirt list,laundry list.
一份內幕清單，詳細清單
lsraeli lntelligence,five years ago,compiled blackmail intel.
以色列情報部五年前收集的敲詐情報
Corrupt agents,German lntelligence, Ml6. . .
包括腐敗特工，德國聯邦情報局，軍情六局
ClA?
中情局？
Yes.
是的
We got to get away.
我們得走了
We got to get out of here.
我們得離開這裏
Ah, shit.
啊，該死
Don't, don't, don't.
別，別，別
No, don't leave me here,please.
不，別把我丟在這裏，拜託
Don't do it.
別這樣做
Matt?
馬特？
Hey.
嘿
How you doing?
你怎麼樣？
I'm proud of you.
我為你以及
And what you pulled off.
你所做到的感到自豪
You're going to make a hell of a case officer.
你會成為一名出色的案件官員
Where's Frost?
弗羅斯特在哪裏？
He's gone.
他走了
Place is a wreck.Blood everywhere.
房子破壞嚴重，到處都是血跡
Was he injured or. . .
他受傷了還是...
I guess you know he killed Keller.
我猜你知道他殺了凱勒吧
No.
不
I killed Keller.
我殺了凱勒
Frost killed Keller.
弗羅斯特殺了凱勒
He killed Linklater, too.
他還殺了林克萊特
Did he talk about anything? Anything he was after?
他有說什麼嗎？說他在找什麼？
Anything he might have had?
說他可能拿到了什麼？
The file.
資料
The file that you're on.
關於你的資料
Along with a lot of other people.
以及其他許多人的資料
Important people.
都是大人物
Listen to me.
聽我說
What would you do
你會怎麼做
if someone is watching your every move?
如果有人監視你的一舉一動？
Some maybe you're not proud of.
某些你見不得光的事情
And you will have some you're not proud of,believe me.
你總會有些事情見不得光的，相信我
And then tries to use it against you?
然後他們試圖以此對付你呢？
You would do what you have to do.
你會被迫反擊的
Where's the file?
資料在哪裏？
Matt, the file.Where is the file?
馬特，資料，資料在哪裏？
You're a dead man.
你死定了
Yeah, a long time now.
是啊，早就該死了
Frost is here.
弗羅斯特在這裏
Let's go.
我們走
We got him.
我們打中他了
A hell of a job.
幹得不錯
You smell that?
你聞到了嗎？
Pinotage.It's a good grape.Great wine.
品樂塔吉，很好的葡萄品種，釀出的酒很香 （南非特有品種）
Local grape.Pinotage is great. . .
當地葡萄品種，品樂塔吉是很特別的...
I don't want you losing this one.
我不想你丟失這資料
It's worth a lot of money.
它值很多錢
You're a good boy,Matty.
你是個好人，馬特
You know what you are.
你知道自己是什麼人
Hey.
嘿
I know what you're not.
我知道你不是壞人
You're better than me.
你比我更好
No, it's okay,just be better than me.
不，沒關係，要比我更好
You promise me.
答應我
Yeah.
好
Well, let's. . .
好吧，我們...
Let's go.
我們走
I just got to get up.I need to get up.
我得起來，我要起來
Stay.
別動
Hey. . .
嘿...
That's exactly as it happened.
這就是事件起因
Obviously,this situation needs
顯然，處理這事需要
to be handled with a certain amount of finesse.
一定的特殊手段
Has anybody else seen this report?
還有別人看過報告嗎？
No, sir. Not yet.
不，長官，還沒
Matt, I'm sure this comes as no surprise,
馬特，我肯定這不足為奇
but parts of this report are going to have to be altered for national security.
不過出於國家安全考慮報告部分內容需要更改
Which parts, sir?
哪部分，長官？
Well. . .
額...
David Barlow can't be held responsible
大衛·巴洛不能
for what happened to the safe house.
為安全屋發生的事負責
We just don't need the scandal.
我們只是不能有醜聞
But, sir,you and I both know that,that is just not the truth.
但是，長官，你我都明白，這不是真相
People don't want the truth anymore, Matt.
人們不再想知道真相了，馬特
It's too messy.Keeps them up nights.
這太麻煩，會讓他們失眠
I'll tell you what I am willing to do, though.
不過我會告訴你我要怎麼做
I think the Agency has grossly underestimated you,
我覺得情報局嚴重低估了你
and I'm recommending you for a senior case officer position.
我要推薦你當高級案件官員
Provided you still want it.
如果你還想要的話
That's a generous offer, sir.
這真是慷慨的錄用機會，長官
There's just one thing you need to clarify for me.
There』s just one thing you 你只需向我說清一件事
Of course.
當然
Frost may have been carrying some vital intel.
弗羅斯特也許曾攜帶某些重要情報
A file.
一份資料
I'm not seeing that anywhere in this report.
我在報告裏完全沒看到這點
What was on the file, sir?
資料裏有什麼，長官？
Something that,quite frankly,could be very damaging
坦白說，是一些能嚴重危害到
to the Agency and to our allies.
情報局和我們盟友的東西
I don't see why Frost would even mention something like that to me.
我不懂弗羅斯特為何要跟我說這些
No, I suppose he wouldn't,would he?
不，我想他不會的，是吧？
You realize, though,that if that file did leak,
不過你知道如果資料洩露
what would happen to the person responsible?
責任人會是什麼下場吧？
That person would be arrested, sir.
那人會被逮捕，長官
He'd be risking everything.
他要冒極大風險
He'd have enemies in every intelligence agency in the world.
世界上所有情報機構都會成為他的敵人
In the eyes of the CIA,he'd be just like Tobin Frost.
在中情局眼裏他就跟托賓·弗羅斯特一樣
Frost didn't say anything about a file, sir.
弗羅斯特完全沒提什麼資料，長官
All right, son.
好的，孩子
Take a few days off.
休幾天假吧
We'll get you started next week.
下周我們再讓你上班
Thank you.
謝謝
And think about our conversation,would you?
好好想想我們的談話，好嗎？
Will do.
我會的
I'll take it from here, sir.
我會記住的，長官
and other media outlets
...其它媒體
received a controversial file from an anonymous source.
收到了來自匿名者的一份爭議文件
The international intelligence community is still reeling
國際情報界仍對如此大量的絕密文件遭洩露
from the release of so many highly classified documents
以及中情局，德國聯邦情報局和軍情六局
and the revelations of widespread corruption and criminaI activity
大範圍的腐敗和犯罪活動遭披露
at the CIA,the BND, and MI6.
處於震驚之中
is in an uproar over the Iack
...對於英國情報機構的監管缺失
of oversight given to British Intelligence,
引發一片嘩然
demanding accountabiIity of the rogue agents.
要求目無法紀的特工人員對此負責
Officials at Ml6 are fully cooperating.
軍情六局官員正全力配合調查
Chancellor Merkel insists that the BND
總理默克爾堅稱德聯邦情報局
has already identified the corrupt agents
已經發現了腐敗特工
and contained the intelligence breach.
並遏制了情報洩露
She has ensured her internationaI counterparts...
她已向她的國際盟友保證...
Indictments are now expected within the week,
本周預計將舉行公訴
and Congress has demanded that Deputy Director Harlan Whitford
國會已要求副局長哈蘭·威特福德
testify before a Senate subcommittee
在參議院小組委員會
in an effort to determine how many peopIe
調查研究中情局具體涉案人數
at the CIA are involved in this
以及腐敗嚴重程度
and just how far up the corruption reaches.
之前出庭作證